[{"answer": "He was beating me.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 15, "question": "And what was he physically doing to you?", "qSentId": 14}, {"answer": "No, actually, Piers, I started writing this book in 2008, and I kept writing and kept writing and there was always something that was coming up that prevented me from actually putting it out.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 40, "question": "Was it Michael dying that motivated you to write this new book?", "qSentId": 39}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 47, "question": "You did?", "qSentId": 46}, {"answer": "-- down it came.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 55, "question": "Oh yes, everything changes, doesn't it?", "qSentId": 54}, {"answer": "That's -- that's what hurts me more than anything else because he could have started over.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 63, "question": "Do you think he -- if he had lived, would he have ever had a chance to start over, Michael, do you think?", "qSentId": 62}, {"answer": "It was a very difficult task for me to start over because there were so many different interruptions when I was about to start over, and I would have to put everything on the back burner but I think that in everybody's life we go through different journeys and different paths and it doesn't always take us the way that we think it's going to take us.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 71, "question": "How has it been for you starting over?", "qSentId": 70}, {"answer": "She is.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 87, "question": "Yes, isn't she adorable?", "qSentId": 86}, {"answer": "And I thought --", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 90, "question": "Jan would say that, wouldn't she?", "qSentId": 89}, {"answer": "Well, I think what it is, Piers, is that when you grow up in the spotlight that everything is magnetized and everything is totally actually blown out of proportion.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 115, "question": "I mean, for all of you it's been very, very tough surviving that period, isn't it?", "qSentId": 114}, {"answer": "I would love to say, yes, we're closer than we've ever been but it's really interesting, Piers, because when -- when a loved one in your family and Michael was the first that we've lost.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 125, "question": "Are you -- are you, oddly, because of the tragedy of Michael, as a family, are you oddly closer now than you've ever been do you think?", "qSentId": 124}, {"answer": "When I look back on it now, it was fun times, it was wonderful times.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 151, "question": "When you -- when you look back on it now, do you feel that?", "qSentId": 150}, {"answer": "I know.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 162, "question": "What are you getting at?", "qSentId": 161}, {"answer": "I didn't want to go into show business.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 167, "question": "Do you ever wish you hadn't gone into show business?", "qSentId": 166}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 196, "question": "Did you ever feel that in his relentless pursuit for you guys to be successful, that the relationship you had with him crossed the line, that it became abusive in any way?", "qSentId": 195}, {"answer": "But, as you grow older -- yes, I got one spanking.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 204, "question": "Did he hit you then?", "qSentId": 203}, {"answer": "Joseph.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 217, "question": "What did you call him?", "qSentId": 216}, {"answer": "Yes, of course.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 225, "question": "Do you still call him Joseph?", "qSentId": 224}, {"answer": "I don't know.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 229, "question": "But if you called him dad, what would happen?", "qSentId": 228}, {"answer": "Exactly the same.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 234, "question": "Do I?", "qSentId": 233}, {"answer": "Very well.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 238, "question": "How do you get on with him now?", "qSentId": 237}, {"answer": "I do.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 244, "question": "Do you think modern parents are a bit soft with their kids?", "qSentId": 243}, {"answer": "I have pretty strong words with them.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 263, "question": "Well, what do you say when they speak back?", "qSentId": 262}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 265, "question": "Really?", "qSentId": 264}, {"answer": "No, I'm like you, I'm big on respect.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 267, "question": "And then do they learn from that or?", "qSentId": 266}, {"answer": "My mother was very quiet.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 276, "question": "Did your mother have a kind of slightly complicated relationship with the way your father treated you all or did she go along with it completely?", "qSentId": 275}, {"answer": "Yes, all the time.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 281, "question": "Has he ever told you he loves you?", "qSentId": 280}, {"answer": "When we were younger -- no, no.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 284, "question": "But only now, he didn't when you -- when you were younger, right?", "qSentId": 283}, {"answer": "ACKSON: I think I told him first, I said, \"Joseph, I love you very, very much, and you mean the world to me, I want you to know that.\"", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 286, "question": "Do you remember the first time he said that?", "qSentId": 285}, {"answer": "Yes, and you must remember something which is very interesting is that I don't care who you are in life, everybody is looking for love.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 291, "question": "Really?", "qSentId": 290}, {"answer": "He never had love himself and so, how -- if you don't --", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 310, "question": "So, he never really had love himself?", "qSentId": 309}, {"answer": "Yes, he has, he did say that to him, yes, absolutely.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 319, "question": "Did Michael ever say I love you to Joseph, do you know?", "qSentId": 318}, {"answer": "It started with my having to go to Japan and my mother wasn't able to go with me, and she asked my father if he could go with me to Japan and my father wasn't able to go with me.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 338, "question": "I've got say -- I mean, he comes over as a complete monster in this book and it sort of prompts the question, when I talk to you now, you seem intelligent, you seem quite worldly-wise, how did you ever get together with a man like this in the first place?", "qSentId": 337}, {"answer": "I couldn't understand why.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 347, "question": "How did you feel when he did that?", "qSentId": 346}, {"answer": "My family was there.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 358, "question": "Why weren't they steaming in to save you?", "qSentId": 357}, {"answer": "I walked out many, many times.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 379, "question": "Did you love him?", "qSentId": 378}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 383, "question": "You never loved him?", "qSentId": 382}, {"answer": "It was shortly after we were together.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 392, "question": "But when did he first start being physically abusive to you?", "qSentId": 391}, {"answer": "He was beating me.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 405, "question": "And what was he physically doing to you?", "qSentId": 404}, {"answer": "No, it wasn't.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 458, "question": "Was that the moment you broke free?", "qSentId": 457}, {"answer": "I don't know how he reacted at the time.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 535, "question": "How did Michael react when you did that?", "qSentId": 534}, {"answer": "I got rid of him.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 550, "question": "How did you get out of his clutches?", "qSentId": 549}, {"answer": "I felt like there was freedom, but I was still nervous.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 596, "question": "When you got out, how did you feel?", "qSentId": 595}, {"answer": "I was at home when I heard that he had passed.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 619, "question": "Where were you when you heard that he died?", "qSentId": 618}, {"answer": "Here at home in L.A., yes.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 621, "question": "Hear in Los Angeles?", "qSentId": 620}, {"answer": "My father had kept calling and telling me to get over to his house, because I live about two or three minutes away from him, and to go over to his house.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 623, "question": "How did you hear?", "qSentId": 622}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 670, "question": "Did you see Michael, after he passed?", "qSentId": 669}, {"answer": "Yea it was closure.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 697, "question": "It's like they had shed all the tears then?", "qSentId": 696}, {"answer": "Absolutely.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 702, "question": "Do you still think that?", "qSentId": 701}, {"answer": "I will never ever think differently.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 705, "question": "Why are you so sure?", "qSentId": 704}, {"answer": "The people that were involved in his life.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 709, "question": "Who were going to murder him?", "qSentId": 708}, {"answer": "I'm going to make sure we do.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 736, "question": "Do you think we'll ever find out the truth?", "qSentId": 735}, {"answer": "The kids are doing very well.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 741, "question": "Latoya, how are the kids doing now, Michael's children?", "qSentId": 740}, {"answer": "She's doing a great job, fabulous job.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 753, "question": "What sort of job is she doing, do you think?", "qSentId": 752}, {"answer": "I would tell him that I'm sorry that I wasn't there to help him to start over.", "docId": "110621pmt", "aSentId": 763, "question": "If you had the chance to talk to Michael again, what would you say to him, that you never had a chance to maybe?", "qSentId": 762}]